

Jeraldy D.
Full Stack Software Engineer

General info

Work experience Location

6 years total Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania, United Re-

public Of

Time zone: UTC+1

Top technologies

JavaScript	5+ years experience	12345+
Django	5+ years experience	12345+
Python	5+ years experience	12345+
React	4 years experience	1 2 3 4 5+
.NET Framework	3 years experience	1 2 3 4 5+

Technologies



Bio

Detail-oriented software development professional and team leader with proficiency in analyzing existing systems to discover issues and inconsistencies. Achievement-oriented professional with a solid background in overseeing system architecture, defining goals, and managing project progress with both local and remote teams. Organized and systematic team player with a background in agile development environments and scrum methodology.

Main tech stack

- JavaScript: >5 years professional experience
- React: >4 years professional experience
- Python: >5 years professional experience
- Django: >5 years professional experience

Jobs of interest

I'm interested in Senior developer jobs, where I work with my main technologies.

Experience

Software Engineer 03/2019 - now

Ministry of Finance & Planning (Tanzania/Dodoma)

3 years and 8 months

Worked on creating a high-quality government account package.

Implemented the frontend logic using JavaScript, React + Redux, and Bootstrap for CSS. The backend logic uses .NET MVC and MySQL Database.

I also worked on the integration of the platform with the Bank of Tanzania and other commercial banks like NMB, CRDB, and NBC.

Other tools I used in this project are Tortoise SVN for version control, Hangfire for executing background jobs, and Visual Studio Code for code editing.

With this package, the government can track payments, control its budget, manage purchases and generate various financial reports. The government has saved approx. TZS 5 Billion annual licenses from terminating the use of commercial software which are very expensive and challenging to manage.

React MySQL JavaScript ASP.NET MVC CSS Redux Bootstrap

Software Engineer 09/2018 - 02/2019

A-Trader (Tanzania/Dar es Salaam)

5 months

Designed and coded the trading platform components in an agile environment utilizing a test-driven development approach.

I worked on the backend part to create APIs using Django, Django-rest-framework, and PostgreSQL database.

I used JWT to authenticate endpoints, Celery, and RabbitMQ for executing background tasks.

On the front I used JavaScript, React + Redux, and CSS.

I prepared the deployment environment using Nginx, Gunicorn, Virtualenv, Supervisord, and PostgreSQL. Successfully deployed the application in the Linux machine on Digital Ocean.

The project enabled people with less or no knowledge of trading to buy and sell stocks using an Al-powered recommendation engine.

Agile Celery PostgreSQL JavaScript JWT RabbitMQ NGINX Linux Redux Python

React HTML CSS Django Rest Framework

Full Stack Software Engineer

01/2018 - 08/2018

Mobile Power (Tanzania/Dar es Salaam)

7 months

I built the DSTV Sales app using Flutter, React + Redux, and CSS on the front end.

I created the backend logic using Django, Django-rest-framework, and PostgreSQL database.

Using git for code versioning management, and VPS for hosting, setting up Nginx and PostgreSQL for deployment.

I also worked on training end-users on how to use the application to achieve various tasks.

This project enabled the DStv company to track its sales information. The company can now make various business and marketing decisions based on this information.

Git Redux PostgreSQL CSS NGINX React Django Rest Flutter

Tech Evangelist 02/2017 - 02/2018

Python Tanzania (Tanzania)

1 year

I joined this peer learning community with a mission to share my knowledge of python programming and improve my knowledge from experienced members.

As a tech evangelist, I had an opportunity to teach the fundamentals of python programming and its various applications.

Through this community, I got introduced to various applications of python such as Machine learning, Data science, and web development using Django and Flask.

I learned to derive various neural network equations and implemented them from scratch using NumPy and Java.

I implemented an app to recognize banknotes using Flutter, NumPy, Tensorflow, and Transfer Learning Technique on a pre-trained model.

Funded by Black in Al organization to attend the Neural Information Processing Systems conference in the U.S (2017).

Award to attend the Deep Learning Indaba, in South Africa (2018) funded by Google and Facebook.

 Python
 Tensorflow
 Numpy
 Artificial Intelligence
 Django
 Flask
 Machine Learning

Education

The University of Dodoma

10/2013 - 10/2017

BSc, Telecommunications Engineering

4 years

Languages

English

Fluent

Swahili

Native